João Victor Palhares Barbosa

+55 19 98103-9387 | joao@palhares.dev | falejoaovictor@hotmail.com linkedin.com/in/joao-palhares/ | lattes.cnpq.br/7839491070550503 | github.com/jvpalhares

Summary

NLP Engineer, Data Scientist, Data & Analytics, +5 years of experience with programming, RASA Chatbot Developer, IIoT & IoT Developer, DevOps Developer, experience working at Cognitive Computing Innovation Studio. Particularly interested in Artificial Intelligence for Medicine, Robotics, Mobile Robotics, Autonomous Guided Vehicles, Robotics with BioMechanics, Robotics Prostheses, Computer Vision, MLOps, SKLearn, PyTorch, TensorFlow, methods of Deep Learning: Convolutional Neural Networks and Recurrent Neural Networks. Currently working with RASA in a project with over 30 Million exchanged messages per month.

Education

Arthur de Azevedo Technological Faculty - FATEC Mogi Mirim

2020 - 2022

Concentration: Industrial Mechatronics Technology

Technical College of Limeira of the State University of Campinas - COTIL UNICAMP

2017 - 2019

Concentration: Computer Technician

Professional Experience

NLP Engineer – Compass.uol

July 2021 - (Current)

I. Currently working with RASA Chatbot at PagSeguro PagBank.

Intern - Development of Artificial Intelligence to Chatbots - Compass.uol

April 2021 - July 2021

- I. During the interview process, 4 tests were created, I had the opportunity to develop an API, use OOP with Python, use MongoDB, create a Neural Network of Regression, Neural Network of Classification, Data Visualization, also had a chance to create a diabetes classifier for diabetes prevention through Machine Learning, and make Sentimental Analysis of articles with SpaCy using MultinomialNB and RandomForestClassifier.
- II. In the end, we created a chatbot RASA to FATEC Arthur de Azevedo.

Intern – Firmware Developer – Phi Innovations

Jan 2021 - Apr 2021

I. Working with C/C++ programming and NuttX on STM32 - Nucleo L152RE & ESP8266.

Intern – Developer & Tester IoT – Phi Innovations

Jun 2020 - Apr 2021

- I. Working with IoT Technologies: MODBUS, MQTT, IoT Gateway application, Node-Red, InfluxDB, Grafana, Linux, CodeSys, Elipse SCADA, IoT Security, among others. Programming with C, C#, C++, QT, Node.js, and JavaScript, STM32, Testing Firmware, and Applications for the customers. Knowledge in electronics, programming, and conversation with customers. Creation of documents to cover new technologies and work methodology.
- II. Lastly, instructing new employees.

Intern – Full-Stack Developer – Valore Marketing and Technology

Aug 2019 - Dec 2019

I. Working with full-stack Technologies on Web Development: CodeIgniter (Framework), PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and others. Creating custom Web pages and systems for customers.

Intern – Analyst of Information Tecnology (DevOps) – Wide Software

Dec 2018 - Jan 2019

I. Working with DevOps Technologies: AWS Cloud (Amazon Web Services - EC2, Route53, S3, IAM, APIGateway, ELB, AutoScalling, and others), Jenkins, Zabbix, Puppet, Git, NGINX, PHP-FPM, MongoDB, ElasticSearch, MySQL and Apache Kafka. Programming with Shell Script Bash, SH Linux for triggers on Grafana and managing, configuring, analyzing, installing, and updating servers. Lastly documentations on Jira Software - Atlassian and agile methodology - Kanban.

Previous Experiences Omitted

Prior to Dec 2018

Honors & Awards

Silver Medal in: ROBOCODE local tournament (LIAG - UNICAMP)

Oct 2020

Issued by UNICAMP Faculty of Technology - FT

Gold Medal in: ROBOCODE local tournament (LIAG - UNICAMP)

Sep 2020

Issued by UNICAMP Faculty of Technology - FT

OBMEP 2019 Honorable Mention Medal - LEVEL 3

Dec 2019

Medal for completing the first and second phases of the OBMEP 2019 test.

Bronze Medal in: ROBOCODE local tournament (LIAG - UNICAMP)

Oct 2019

Issued by UNICAMP Faculty of Technology - FT

Silver Medal in: ROBOCODE local tournament (LIAG - UNICAMP)

Oct 2019

Issued by UNICAMP Faculty of Technology - FT

Medal in: Brazilian Astronomy and Astronautics Olympiad - OBA

Nov 2016

Bronze medal, earning a grade of 8.75 in the OBA test - Brazilian Astronomy and Astronautics Olympiad.

1TPR - Brazilian Robotics Olympiad: 1st Paulista Robotics Tournament

May 2016

1st Paulista Robotics Tournament with rules of: Brazilian Robotics Olympiad (OBR).

Volunteering

Programming and Arduino Tutoring

Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

Education - Arthur de Azevedo Technological Faculty - FATEC Mogi Mirim

Student & Room Representative

Jan 2020 - (Current)

Education - Arthur de Azevedo Technological Faculty - FATEC Mogi Mirim

Tutoring and Presenter

Sep 2018 - Aug 2019

Education - Campinas State University - UNICAMP

Previous Experiences Omitted

Prior to Sep 2018

Licenses & Certifications

AWS Partner: Accreditation (Technical)	Dec 2021
Check it out: credly.com/badges/d2745bd2-fdbe-4dba-81a9-dbc16be10261	
AWS Partner: Machine Learning on AWS (Technical) (Portuguese)	Dec 2021
Credential ID: E-086J3V	
Rasa Developer Certification	Oct 2021
Credential ID: FLTSDLDTDL-HDRHJRKH-WNWTFBWFFW	
Data Science: Analysis for Health and Medicine	Oct 2021
Check it out: cursos.alura.com.br/certificate/a4b4e07f-edda-410c-b15b-ba895a8e4d6e	
MLOps: Machine Learning & API's	Oct 2021
Check it out: cursos.alura.com.br/certificate/84ca3000-71cd-4c66-a970-08e05b14a6c1	
Neural Networks: Deep Learning with PyTorch	Apr 2021

Check it out: cursos.alura.com.br/certificate/07f6858e-6272-4d1e-9969-6e85260123b4

Skills & Abilities

Previous Experiences Omitted

Programming / Markup / Data API / Technologies

C/C++, C#, QT, Python, RASA, NLP, SpaCy, RPA, OpenCV, Computer Vision, MLOps, AutoML, SKLearn, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Markdown, Git, Github, PHP, HTML, CSS3, Bootstrap, Node.js, JavaScript, CodeIgniter, Bash, Shell Script, MySQL, MongoDB, ElasticSearch, InfluxDB, Jenkins, Zabbix, AWS (Amazon Web Services), Amazon EC2, Amazon S3, Amazon Lex, Watson Assistant, AWS IoT, Nginx, Apache Kafka, Kubernetes, Docker, MQTT, Arduino, Esp8266, STM32, NuttX, Raspberry Pi, ModBus, Node-Red, Grafana, CodeSys, Elipse Scada.

Prior to Mar 2021

Methods

Casual Inference and Experimental Design & Thinking, Mathematical & Statistical bases, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing (NLP), Documentation reading and writing purposes.